Finding Aid for the Yvar Mikhashoff Collection of Reel to Reel Tapes, 1961-1984
State University of New York at Buffalo. Music Library
- Reel to reel tapes added from other University at Buffalo sources with Mikhashoff as performer or composer, circa 1970-1981, V.; Item 185-216
  - Yvar Mikhashoff Collection of Reel to reel tapes, Tape 206, 1978-11-30, 1 10.5 inch reel; Container title: Bussottioperaballet 11/30/78 Performers: Mikhashoff, piano, speaker; William Kirkpatrick, dancer, choreographer Recording location: University at Buffalo, Baird Recital Hall Printed program
    Contents: Bussotti: Foglio d'album (5:22) -- Ankibathes (2:39) -- Musica per amici (4:51) -- Parfum (4:00) -- Sensitivo (12:32) -- Novelletta (10:43) -- Per tre (8:13) -- Foglio d'album (5:45)
    Preservation archival master file(s): ubmu0001_4_206_01am.wav
    Production master files file: ubmu0001_4_206_01-01pm.wav, ubmu0001_4_206_01-02pm.wav, ubmu0001_4_206_01-03pm.wav, ubmu0001_4_206_01-04pm.wav, ubmu0001_4_206_01-05pm.wav, ubmu0001_4_206_01-06pm.wav, ubmu0001_4_206_01-07pm.wav, ubmu0001_4_206_01-08pm.wav
    Service copy file: ubmu0001_4_206_01-01sc.mp3, ubmu0001_4_206_01-02sc.mp3, ubmu0001_4_206_01-03sc.mp3, ubmu0001_4_206_01-04sc.mp3, ubmu0001_4_206_01-05sc.mp3, ubmu0001_4_206_01-06sc.mp3, ubmu0001_4_206_01-07sc.mp3, ubmu0001_4_206_01-08sc.mp3
  - Yvar Mikhashoff Collection of Reel to reel tapes, Tape 207, 1978-12-19, 1 10.5 inch reel; Container title: Rehfuss, Knittel, Mikhashoff Fac. Rec. 12/19/78 Performers: Mikhashoff, piano; Suze Leal Rehfuss, mezzo-soprano; Weronika Knittel, violin Recording location: University at Buffalo, Baird Recital Hall Printed program with changes in order noted inserted Derivative files created: 11 (Box 14, Item 207)
    Contents: Caldara: Vaghe Luci e troppo crudo (6:03); T. Arne: The soldier tir'd of war's alarms (3:40); Comments; Scelsi: Sonata No. 2. Lento meditativo (8:45); Comments; Villa Lobos: Three Brazillian folksongs (8:53); Comments; Tchaikovsky: Pauline's aria (4:10) -- At the ball -- Don't believe, my love -- None but the lonely heart (11:02); Prokofiev: Sonata for violin and piano no. 2 (23:32)
    Preservation archival master file(s): ubmu0001_4_207_01am.wav
    Production master files file: ubmu0001_4_207_01-01pm.wav, ubmu0001_4_207_01-02pm.wav, ubmu0001_4_207_01-03pm.wav, ubmu0001_4_207_01-04pm.wav, ubmu0001_4_207_01-05pm.wav, ubmu0001_4_207_01-06pm.wav, ubmu0001_4_207_01-07pm.wav, ubmu0001_4_207_01-08pm.wav, ubmu0001_4_207_01-09pm.wav, ubmu0001_4_207_01-10pm.wav, ubmu0001_4_207_01-11pm.wav, ubmu0001_4_207_01-12pm.wav
    Service copy file: ubmu0001_4_207_01-01sc.mp3, ubmu0001_4_207_01-02sc.mp3, ubmu0001_4_207_01-03sc.mp3, ubmu0001_4_207_01-04sc.mp3, ubmu0001_4_207_01-05sc.mp3, ubmu0001_4_207_01-06sc.mp3, ubmu0001_4_207_01-07sc.mp3, ubmu0001_4_207_01-08sc.mp3, ubmu0001_4_207_01-09sc.mp3, ubmu0001_4_207_01-10sc.mp3, ubmu0001_4_207_01-11sc.mp3, ubmu0001_4_207_01-12sc.mp3
  - Yvar Mikhashoff Collection of Reel to reel tapes, Tape 208, 1980-01-28, 1 10.5 inch reel; Container title: Bon bon filled with snow 1/28/80 Performers: Mikhashoff, piano; Thomas Halpin, violin Recording location: University at Buffalo, Baird Recital Hall Printed program inserted for concert titled A bonbon filled with snow: music of Grieg and Debussy Derivative files created: 10 (Box 14, Item 208)
    Contents: Debussy: La Fille aux cheveux de lin (2:40) -- Il pleure dans mon coeur (3:30) -- Minstrels (2:10); Grieg: Sonata for violin and piano no. III, Op. 45 (24:45); Puck, Op. 71, no. 3 (piano); Puck, op. 71, no. 3 (violin and piano) (2:00); Debussy: La Danse de Puck (piano) (2:35) -- La danse de Puck, transcribed for violin and piano by Halpin and Mikhashoff (2:55) -- Sonata pour violin et piano (13:45); [Encores] Grieg: Puck (1:00); Debussy: Puck (3:00)
    Preservation archival master file(s): ubmu0001_4_208_01am.wav
    Production master files file: ubmu0001_4_208_01-01pm.wav, ubmu0001_4_208_01-02pm.wav, ubmu0001_4_208_01-03pm.wav, ubmu0001_4_208_01-04pm.wav, ubmu0001_4_208_01-05pm.wav, ubmu0001_4_208_01-06pm.wav, ubmu0001_4_208_01-07pm.wav, ubmu0001_4_208_01-08pm.wav, ubmu0001_4_208_01-09pm.wav, ubmu0001_4_208_01-10pm.wav, ubmu0001_4_208_01-11pm.wav
    Service copy file: ubmu0001_4_208_01-01sc.mp3, ubmu0001_4_208_01-02sc.mp3, ubmu0001_4_208_01-03sc.mp3, ubmu0001_4_208_01-04sc.mp3, ubmu0001_4_208_01-05sc.mp3, ubmu0001_4_208_01-06sc.mp3, ubmu0001_4_208_01-07sc.mp3, ubmu0001_4_208_01-08sc.mp3, ubmu0001_4_208_01-09sc.mp3, ubmu0001_4_208_01-10sc.mp3, ubmu0001_4_208_01-11sc.mp3
  - Yvar Mikhashoff Collection of Reel to reel tapes, Tape 209, 1980-04-30, 1 10.5 inch reel; Container title: Yvar Mikhashoff - piano 4/30/80 Performers: Mikhashoff, piano; James Kasprowicz, trombone; Joanne Lowe, viola; Farley Pearce, cello Recording location: University at Buffalo, Baird Recital Hall Printed program inserted Derivative files created: 7 (Box 14, Item 209)
    Contents: Robert Palmer: Second piano sonata (13:23); Smit: Scena cambiatal (12:15); Debussy: Preludes (8) (26:00); Beeson: Fifth piano sonata (14:42); Thomson: Three portraits, transcribed by Mikhashoff. Madame Dubost Chez elle -- Russell Hitchcock, reading -- Ettie Stettheiner (3:28); Liszt. Consolation no. 3 (4:55); Liszt-Mikhashoff: Hungarian rhapsody no. 19 (8:30)
    Preservation archival master file(s): ubmu0001_4_209_01am.wav
    Production master files file: ubmu0001_4_209_01-01pm.wav, ubmu0001_4_209_01-02pm.wav, ubmu0001_4_209_01-03pm.wav, ubmu0001_4_209_01-04pm.wav, ubmu0001_4_209_01-05pm.wav, ubmu0001_4_209_01-06pm.wav, ubmu0001_4_209_01-07pm.wav, ubmu0001_4_209_01-08pm.wav, ubmu0001_4_209_01-09pm.wav, ubmu0001_4_209_01-10pm.wav
    Service copy file: ubmu0001_4_209_01-01sc.mp3, ubmu0001_4_209_01-02sc.mp3, ubmu0001_4_209_01-03sc.mp3, ubmu0001_4_209_01-04sc.mp3, ubmu0001_4_209_01-05sc.mp3, ubmu0001_4_209_01-06sc.mp3, ubmu0001_4_209_01-07sc.mp3, ubmu0001_4_209_01-08sc.mp3, ubmu0001_4_209_01-09sc.mp3, ubmu0001_4_209_01-10sc.mp3
  - Yvar Mikhashoff Collection of Reel to reel tapes, Tape 210, 1980-05-13, 1 10.5 inch reel; Container title: Furniture music etc. 5/13/80 Performers: Mikhashoff, Aki Takahashi, Arthur Weissman, Elise Alaimo, Rick McGirr, piano; Thomas Halpin, violin; Darlene Reynard, bassoon; David Moebs, clarinet; Farley Pearce, cello; Joan Calken, actress Recording location: University at Buffalo, Baird Recital Hall Printed program inserted for concert titled Furniture music etcetera: music of Satie and Cage; world premiere of Furniture music Derivative files created: 19 (Box 115, Item 210)
    Contents: Satie: Trois petites pieces Montées (4:01) -- Sports and diversion, transcribed by Mikhashoff (15:40) -- Entr'acte (13:57); Cage: A room -- Cheap imitation -- A valentine out of season (12:56) -- Cage, Satie: Furniture music etcetera (19:46)
    Preservation archival master file(s): ubmu0001_4_210_01am.wav
    Production master files file: ubmu0001_4_210_01-01pm.wav, ubmu0001_4_210_01-02pm.wav, ubmu0001_4_210_01-03pm.wav, ubmu0001_4_210_01-04pm.wav, ubmu0001_4_210_01-05pm.wav, ubmu0001_4_210_01-06pm.wav, ubmu0001_4_210_01-07pm.wav
    Service copy file: ubmu0001_4_210_01-01sc.mp3, ubmu0001_4_210_01-02sc.mp3, ubmu0001_4_210_01-03sc.mp3, ubmu0001_4_210_01-04sc.mp3, ubmu0001_4_210_01-05sc.mp3, ubmu0001_4_210_01-06sc.mp3, ubmu0001_4_210_01-07sc.mp3
  - Yvar Mikhashoff Collection of Reel to reel tapes, Tape 211, 1981-02-28, 1 10.5 inch reel; Container title: Paris in the twenties 2/28/81 Performers: Mikhashoff, piano; Gary Burgess, tenor; Thomas Halpin, violin Recording location: University at Buffalo, Baird Recital Hall Printed program inserted for concert titled Paris in the twenties Derivative files created: 8 (Box 115, Item 211)
    Contents: Milhaud: Saudades do Brasil (10:00); Copland: Old poem and pastoral (5:30); Villa-Lobos: Sertaneja (3:00); Faure: Diane, Selene (2:00); Ravel: Berceuse (3:15); Satie: Ludions (4:35); Antheil: Sonata no. 2 (8:15); Milhaud: Quatre poemes de Catulle (4:30); Roussel: Adagio (5:35); Stravinsky: Minuet and finale (4:45); Poulenc: Poeme de Ronsard; Auric: B (4:15); Copland: Poet's song -- Dirge in woods (5:00); Thomson: Five easy pieces (2:30); Copland: Nocturne and Ukele serenade (9:20)
    Preservation archival master file(s): ubmu0001_4_211_01am.wav
    Production master files file: ubmu0001_4_211_01-01pm.wav, ubmu0001_4_211_01-02pm.wav, ubmu0001_4_211_01-03pm.wav, ubmu0001_4_211_01-04pm.wav, ubmu0001_4_211_01-05pm.wav, ubmu0001_4_211_01-06pm.wav, ubmu0001_4_211_01-07pm.wav, ubmu0001_4_211_01-08pm.wav, ubmu0001_4_211_01-09pm.wav, ubmu0001_4_211_01-10pm.wav, ubmu0001_4_211_01-11pm.wav, ubmu0001_4_211_01-12pm.wav, ubmu0001_4_211_01-13pm.wav, ubmu0001_4_211_01-14pm.wav, ubmu0001_4_211_01-15pm.wav, ubmu0001_4_211_01-16pm.wav, ubmu0001_4_211_01-17pm.wav, ubmu0001_4_211_01-18pm.wav, ubmu0001_4_211_01-19pm.wav
    Service copy file: ubmu0001_4_211_01-01sc.mp3, ubmu0001_4_211_01-02sc.mp3, ubmu0001_4_211_01-03sc.mp3, ubmu0001_4_211_01-04sc.mp3, ubmu0001_4_211_01-05sc.mp3, ubmu0001_4_211_01-06sc.mp3, ubmu0001_4_211_01-07sc.mp3, ubmu0001_4_211_01-08sc.mp3, ubmu0001_4_211_01-09sc.mp3, ubmu0001_4_211_01-10sc.mp3, ubmu0001_4_211_01-11sc.mp3, ubmu0001_4_211_01-12sc.mp3, ubmu0001_4_211_01-13sc.mp3, ubmu0001_4_211_01-14sc.mp3, ubmu0001_4_211_01-15sc.mp3, ubmu0001_4_211_01-16sc.mp3, ubmu0001_4_211_01-17sc.mp3, ubmu0001_4_211_01-18sc.mp3, ubmu0001_4_211_01-19sc.mp3
  - Yvar Mikhashoff Collection of Reel to reel tapes, Tape 212, 1981-03-25, 1 10.5 inch reel; Container title: Mikhashoff, Manes, Halpin 3/25/81 Performers: Mikhashoff, Stephen Manes, Anthony de Mare, piano; Thomas Halpin, violin Recording location: University at Buffalo, Baird Recital Hall Printed program inserted for concert titled Bela Bartok: March 25, 1881, A centennial concert Derivative files created: 7 (Box 115, Item 212)
    Contents: Bartok: Three easy pieces (5:33) -- Three Hungarian folksongs (4:00) -- Rumanian folk dances (6:00) -- Improvisations on Hungarian folksongs (13:30) -- Seven pieces (8:45) -- Out of doors (15:20) -- Bartokiana, arranged from Mikrokosmos for violin and piano by Mikhashoff (13:30) -- Adagio religioso (9:10)
    Preservation archival master file(s): ubmu0001_4_212_01am.wav
    Production master files file: ubmu0001_4_212_01-01pm.wav, ubmu0001_4_212_01-02pm.wav, ubmu0001_4_212_01-03pm.wav, ubmu0001_4_212_01-04pm.wav, ubmu0001_4_212_01-05pm.wav, ubmu0001_4_212_01-06pm.wav, ubmu0001_4_212_01-07pm.wav, ubmu0001_4_212_01-08pm.wav
    Service copy file: ubmu0001_4_212_01-01sc.mp3, ubmu0001_4_212_01-02sc.mp3, ubmu0001_4_212_01-03sc.mp3, ubmu0001_4_212_01-04sc.mp3, ubmu0001_4_212_01-05sc.mp3, ubmu0001_4_212_01-06sc.mp3, ubmu0001_4_212_01-07sc.mp3, ubmu0001_4_212_01-08sc.mp3
  - Yvar Mikhashoff Collection of Reel to reel tapes, Tape 213, 1981-06-25, 1 10.5 inch reel; Container title: Liszt, Satie, and Mikhashoff Reel 1 6/25/81 Performers: Mikhashoff, piano Recording location: University at Buffalo, Baird Recital Hall Reel 1 of 2 Printed program inserted for concert titled Liszt, Satie, and modern friends, first of a series titled Retrospectives and perspectives for piano: four farewells to Baird Hall; remainder of concert on Tape 214 Derivative files created: 6 (Box 115, Item 213)
    Contents: Satie: Ogive no. 1 -- Sarabande no. 1; Cage: 49 waltzes for the five boroughs; Nielsen: Arabesque, opus 3 no. 5; Grieg: Bells, opus 54 no. 6; Ib Nørholm: A discourse on time
    Preservation archival master file(s): ubmu0001_4_213_01am.wav
    Production master files file: ubmu0001_4_213_01-01pm.wav, ubmu0001_4_213_01-02pm.wav, ubmu0001_4_213_01-03pm.wav, ubmu0001_4_213_01-04pm.wav, ubmu0001_4_213_01-05pm.wav, ubmu0001_4_213_01-06pm.wav, ubmu0001_4_213_01-07pm.wav
    Service copy file: ubmu0001_4_213_01-01sc.mp3, ubmu0001_4_213_01-02sc.mp3, ubmu0001_4_213_01-03sc.mp3, ubmu0001_4_213_01-04sc.mp3, ubmu0001_4_213_01-05sc.mp3, ubmu0001_4_213_01-06sc.mp3, ubmu0001_4_213_01-07sc.mp3
  - Yvar Mikhashoff Collection of Reel to reel tapes, Tape 214, 1981-06-25, 1 10.5 inch reel; Container title: Liszt, Satie, and Mikhashoff Reel 2 6/25/81 Performers: Mikhashoff, piano Recording location: University at Buffalo, Baird Recital Hall Reel 2 of 2 Printed program inserted in Tape 213 for concert titled Liszt, Satie, and modern friends, first of a series titled Retrospectives and perspectives for piano: four farewells to Baird Hall; remainder of concert on Tape 213 Derivative files created: 12 (Box 115, Item 214)
    Contents: Satie: Ogive no. 3 -- Sarabande no. 3; Wolff: Preludes; Peter Ware: Piscataway; Liszt: The fountains at the Villa d'este; Liszt-Mikhashoff: Hungarian rhapsody no. 19
    Preservation archival master file(s): ubmu0001_4_214_01am.wav
    Production master files file: ubmu0001_4_214_01-01pm.wav, ubmu0001_4_214_01-02pm.wav, ubmu0001_4_214_01-03pm.wav, ubmu0001_4_214_01-04pm.wav, ubmu0001_4_214_01-05pm.wav, ubmu0001_4_214_01-06pm.wav
    Service copy file: ubmu0001_4_214_01-01sc.mp3, ubmu0001_4_214_01-02sc.mp3, ubmu0001_4_214_01-03sc.mp3, ubmu0001_4_214_01-04sc.mp3, ubmu0001_4_214_01-05sc.mp3, ubmu0001_4_214_01-06sc.mp3
  - Yvar Mikhashoff Collection of Reel to reel tapes, Tape 215, 1981-06-27, 1 10.5 inch reel; Container title: Parisian piano - Mikhashoff 6/27/81 Performers: Mikhashoff, piano Recording location: University at Buffalo, Baird Recital Hall Printed program inserted for concert titled Parisian piano (1880-1980), third of a series titled Retrospectives and perspectives for piano: four farewells to Baird Hall Derivative files created: 2 (Box 115, Item 215)
    Contents: Satie: Gymnopedie no. 1; Debussy: Images, Book II. Cloches a travers les feuilles -- Et la lune descend sur la temple qui fut -- Poissons d'or; Satie: Gymnopedie no. 2; Jolas: B for Sonata; Satie: Gymnopedie no. 3; Jean Wiener: Polka, Tango, Java -- New work; Jolas: New work; Debussy: Elegie; Poulenc: Napoli
    Preservation archival master file(s): ubmu0001_4_215_01am.wav
    Production master files file: ubmu0001_4_215_01-01pm.wav, ubmu0001_4_215_01-02pm.wav, ubmu0001_4_215_01-03pm.wav, ubmu0001_4_215_01-04pm.wav, ubmu0001_4_215_01-05pm.wav, ubmu0001_4_215_01-06pm.wav, ubmu0001_4_215_01-07pm.wav, ubmu0001_4_215_01-08pm.wav, ubmu0001_4_215_01-09pm.wav, ubmu0001_4_215_01-10pm.wav, ubmu0001_4_215_01-11pm.wav, ubmu0001_4_215_01-12pm.wav
    Service copy file: ubmu0001_4_215_01-01sc.mp3, ubmu0001_4_215_01-02sc.mp3, ubmu0001_4_215_01-03sc.mp3, ubmu0001_4_215_01-04sc.mp3, ubmu0001_4_215_01-05sc.mp3, ubmu0001_4_215_01-06sc.mp3, ubmu0001_4_215_01-07sc.mp3, ubmu0001_4_215_01-08sc.mp3, ubmu0001_4_215_01-09sc.mp3, ubmu0001_4_215_01-10sc.mp3, ubmu0001_4_215_01-11sc.mp3, ubmu0001_4_215_01-12sc.mp3
  - Yvar Mikhashoff Collection of Reel to reel tapes, Tape 216, 1981-06-28, 1 10.5 inch reel; Container title: Nightclub operas - Mikhashoff 6/28/81 Performers: Mikhashoff, piano; Thomas Halpin, violin; Kyle Peterson, clarinet Recording location: University at Buffalo, Baird Recital Hall Printed program inserted for concert titled Nightclub operas, fourth of a series titled Retrospectives and perspectives for piano: four farewells to Baird Hall; world premiere of this edition of Pianobar (Box 115, Item 216)
    Contents: Bussotti: Pianobar, transcribed and edited by Mikhashoff (45:09); Krenek: Johnny's jazz band: Suite from the opera Jonny spielt auf, transcribed and arranged by Mikhashoff (28:30)
    Preservation archival master file(s): ubmu0001_4_216_01am.wav
    Production master files file: ubmu0001_4_216_01-01pm.wav, ubmu0001_4_216_01-02pm.wav
    Service copy file: ubmu0001_4_216_01-01sc.mp3, ubmu0001_4_216_01-02sc.mp3
Search Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the Library's online catalog.
Subjects
Mikhashoff, Yvar, 1941-1993 -- Archives; Music--20th century; Piano music
Genres
open reel audiotapes; sound recordings; musical performances
Associated Material
Index to composers and performers in the collection
Composer index, with references to item numbers
Albeniz, Isaac 48, 49, 50
Anonymous 13, 51, 52, 110
Antheil, George 102, 109, 113, 114
Ashforth, Alden 177
Auric, Georges 94, 97, 99
Austin, Larry 118, 124, 125, 126
Babbit, Milton 177
Bach, J. S. 13, 14
Bach-Busoni 18
Bach, C. P. E. 42
Baker, Larry 147, 150
Barber, Samuel 109, 113, 114
Bartok, Bela 6, 28, 29, 30, 58, 59, 60, 122
Becker, John J. 109, 111
Beeson, Jack 113, 114, 174
Bennett, Richard Rodney 181
Berenguer, Josep Manuel 158
Berg, Alban 53, 54, 55, 56, 64, 65, 66
Berger, Jean 35
Berio, Luciano 67, 68, 69
Berkmanm Robert 181
Bernstein, Leonard 109, 113, 114
Bieler, Helmut 162
Biscardi, Chester 181
Blacher, Boris 164
Blavet, Michel 11
Brahms, Johannes 1, 13, 14, 15, 28, 29, 30
Brant, Henry 113, 114
Bright, Colin 181
Britten, Benjamin 35
Brown, Earle 81, 113, 114
Bruen, Neily 145, 151
Bussotti, Sylvano 70, 75
Cage, John 40, 41, 58, 59, 60, 71, 72, 82, 91, 113, 114, 115, 177, 181
Capdevila, Merle 159
Carr, Adrian 71, 72
Carr, Benjamin 110
Casella, Alfredo 51, 52
Charpentier, Jacques 9
Chavez, Carlos 101
Chopin, Frederic 6, 19, 28, 29, 30, 32, 33
Colgrass, Michael 42
Constanten, Tom 177
Constantinides, Dinos 163
Copland, Aaron 1, 9, 16, 42, 58, 59, 60, 61, 62, 63, 97, 99-102, 109, 113, 114, 181
Couperin, Francois 32, 33
Cowell, Henry 53, 54, 55, 56, 58, 59, 60, 81, 109, 113, 114
Crawford, Ruth 113, 114
Crumb, George 115
Cummings, Conrad 149
Curran, Alvin 111, 113, 114, 182
Dashow, James 127
Daugherty, Michael 118, 128
Davidovsky, Mario 32, 81, 113, 114, 129
Debussy, Claude 3, 4, 6, 9, 12, 19, 20, 32, 33, 48, 49, 50, 93, 94, 95, 107
DeLeeuw, Ton 71, 72
Dessau, Paul 164
Diemente, Edward 75
Dodge, Charles 130
Dowland, John 13, 14
Duckworth, William 181
Dvorák, Antonin 24, 28, 29, 30
Eisler, Hanns 64, 65, 66, 113, 114
Evangelisti, Franco 75
Falla, Manuel de 11, 18, 28, 29, 30
Farwell, Arthur 110
Faure, Gabriel 11, 97
Felder, David 113, 114, 118, 131
Feldman, Morton 58, 59, 60, 81, 90, 109, 113, 114
Fennimore, Joseph 6, 9, 12, 177
Foss, Lukas 3, 67, 68, 69, 92, 108, 111, 113, 114, 181
Franchetti, Arnold 75
Fricker, P. Racine 17
Gena, Peter 177
Genin, Paul Agricola 11
Gershwin, George 51, 52, 109, 113, 114
Ginastera, Alberto 9, 101
Glass, Philipp 177, 190
Gould, Morton 113, 114
Grainger, Percy 113, 114
Griffes, Charles 109, 110, 113, 114
Guarnieri, Camargo 101
Hachimura, Yoshio 74
Hagen, Peter Albrecht van 110
Handel, George Frideric 35
Harris, Roy 61, 62, 63, 113, 114
Harrison, Lou 113, 114, 177
Hartmann, Karl-Amadeus 164
Hauer, Josef Matthias 53, 54, 55, 56
Haydn, Joseph 13, 14
Heinrich, Anthony Philip 110
Helps, Robert 177
Hennagin, Michael 1
Henze, Hans-Werner 164
Hill, Jackson 181
Hiller, Lejaren 58, 59, 60, 73, 107, 109, 113, 114
Hindemith, Paul 24, 27, 45, 64, 65, 66, 71, 72
Honegger, Arthur 51, 52
Hovhaness, Alan 113, 114
Hoyland, Vic 190
Hudson, Ben 133
Ives, Charles 3, 8, 18, 21, 28, 29, 30, 32, 40, 41, 53-56, 106, 109, 110, 113, 114, 178
Ivey, Jean Eichelberger 134, 148
Jackson, George K. 110
Jaggard, David 181
Janácek, Leoš 10, 28, 29, 30
Jinasek, I. 166
Johnson, Hunter 40, 41, 61, 62, 63, 88, 89, 174
Joplin, Scott 110
Kagel, Mauricio 135
Keane, David 136
Kirchner, Leon 113, 114
Koechlin, Charles 15, 45
Kolb, Barbara 137
Kramer, Jonathan 144, 146
Krauze, Zygmunt 177
Krenek, Ernst 93, 94, 102, 103, 104, 105, 113, 114
Kubik, Ladislav 165, 166
Leone, Tanya 113, 114
Lewin-Richter 161
Ligeti, Gyorgy 118
Lipschutz, Isabelle 8
Liszt, Franz 19, 22, 32, 33, 34, 37, 47, 48, 49, 50, 80
Martin, Charles 42
Martino, Donald 23, 113, 114
Maslanka, David 107
McNabb, Michael 138
Messiaen, Olivier 9, 67, 68, 69, 152
Mikhashoff, Yvar 2, 5, 7, 8, 13, 14, 17, 23, 25, 26, 35, 38, 39, 42-46, 57-60, 116, 117
Milhaud, Darius 4, 45, 93, 94, 98
Miroglio, Francis 167
Molique, Bernard 11
Montague, Stephen 132
Moran, Robert 115, 122, 177
Morley, Thomas 13, 14
Mussorgsky, Modest 24, 28, 29, 30
Mozart, Wolfgang Amadeus 15
Nancarrow, Conlon 109, 113, 114, 118
Norholm, Ib 106
Ornstein, Leo 109, 113, 114
Orrego-Salas, Juan 101
Palmer, Robert 154, 155
Patachich, Ivan 168
Pederson 139
Pender, Scott 181
Peter, John Frederic 110
Philipps, Burril 156
Pickard, Kevin 27
Polonio, Eduardo 160
Porter, Cole 51, 52
Poulenc, Francis 12, 17, 22, 25, 33, 51, 52, 98
Prokofiev, Sergei 9, 53, 54, 55, 56, 83, 84, 85, 86
Rachmaninoff, Sergei 35
Ravel, Maurice 3, 4, 12, 27, 28, 29, 30, 35, 38, 44, 48, 49, 50, 97, 98
Reger, Max 183
Reinagle, Alexander 110
Rezak, I. 166
Riegger, Wallingford 109, 113, 114
Rodrigo, Josquin 11, 27
Rorem, Ned 113, 114
Roussel, Albert 98
Rudhyar, Dane 109, 111, 113, 114, 181
Ruggles, Carl 40, 41, 113, 114
Rzewski, Frederic 106, 107, 111, 113, 114
Sary, Lazlo 181
Satie, Erik 20, 51, 52, 58, 59, 60, 98
Scelsi, Giacinto 75, 92, 119, 120, 121, 169
Schafer, R. Murray 157
Schimmel, William 181
Schmidt, Paul 189
Schoenberg, Arnold 53, 54, 55, 56, 64, 65, 66
Schubert, Franz 22
Schumann, Robert 22, 24
Scriabin, Alexandr 53, 54, 55, 56
Sessions, Roger 177
Sellars, James 61, 62, 63, 75, 82, 111, 118
Shapey, Ralph 113, 114
Smetana, Bedrich 28, 29, 30
Smit, Leo 58, 59, 60, 93, 95, 100
Stalvey, Dorrance 170, 171, 172
Stanley, John 11
Steiger, Rand 193
Stiller, Andrew 23
Stockhausen, Karlheinz 67, 68, 69, 179
Stout, Alan 177
Strauss, Richard 22, 35, 143
Stravinsky, Igor 13, 14, 17, 51, 52, 53, 54, 55, 56, 75, 94, 95, 98, 102
Subotnick, Morton 140, 141
Szekely, Endre 142
Tcherepnin, Ivan 177
Thomson, Virgil 61, 62, 63, 109, 113, 114, 122, 177, 176
Tomasi, Henri 45
Tower, Joan 177
Trimble, Lester 13, 14
Vigeland, Nils 96, 113, 114
Villa-Lobos, Heitor 97, 101
Vivaldi, Antonio 24
Vivaldi-Mikhashoff 25
Wagner, Richard 37
Wagner-Regeny, Rudolf 164
Weber, Carl Maria von 13, 14
Webern, Anton 45, 53, 54, 55, 56, 64, 65, 66
Weill, Kurt 8, 64, 65, 66
White, David Ashley 27
Willey, James 107, 153, 156, 173
Wolff, Christian 71, 72, 82, 106, 112, 113, 114
Young, LaMonte 113, 114
Zappa, Frank 113, 114
Performer index, with references to item numbers
Adcock, Gail (oboe) 64, 65, 66
Anderson, Ronald (trumpet) 149
Andolina, Sal (clarinet) 64, 65, 66
Austin Symphony Orchestra 34
Bacik, Barbara (piano) 28, 29, 30
Baird Contemporary Ensemble 67, 68, 69
Balkin, Laura Mahan (violin) 107
Balkin, Richard (violin) 107
Bates, Stephen (recorders) 57
Bell, Richard (trombone) 64, 65, 66
Bevan, Rosalind 179
Bilson, Malcolm (piano) 154, 155
Bish, Douglas (clarinet) 102
Black, Bonnie (cello) 53, 54, 55, 56
Black, Ira (narrator) 42, 43
Black, Patti (piano) 45
Blustein, Allan (clarinet) 149
Bond, Barbara 36
Bonner, David (flute) 13, 14
Boudler, John (percussion) 67, 68, 69
Brace, Tim (guitar) 57
Bradley, Stephen (electronics) 71, 72, 91
Brotherton, Willo (clarinet) 4
Brown, Richard (percussion) 57
Bruen, Neily (piano) 151
Buffalo String Quartet 37
Burgess, Gary (tenor) 97, 98, 99, 100, 101
Cambiata, Inc. 97, 98, 99, 101
Cambiata Soloists 12, 13, 14, 15, 17, 24, 25, 26, 27, 28, 29, 30, 31, 42, 43, 57, 117
Chamberlain, James (clarinet) 13, 14
Chodos, Amron (clarinet) 23
Christner, Philip (trumpet) 64, 65, 66
Clark, Harry (violincello) 13, 14
Cleveland Orchestra 3
Cobb, John (piano) 177
Cole, Jan (flute) 11
Cole, Jan (flute, recorder, piccolo, alto flute, bass flute) 7
Conlon, Christopher (trumpet) 64, 65, 66
Constant, Marius (conductor) 152
Cooke, Jeff (clarinet) 64, 65, 66
Covert, Mary Ann (piano, 1st work) 154, 155
Crouse, Wayne (viola) 42, 43, 57
Cundy, Rhonda (soprano) 45
Curtin, Phyllis (soprano) 3
D'Amore, Paul (oboe) 64, 65, 66
Dawe, Amy (flute) 64, 65, 66
Dechario, Barbara (harp) 107
Delk, Lesley (soprano) 88, 89
Dent, Frank (speaker) 12
Dick, Robert (flute) 88, 89
Dickinson, [Meriel?] (voice) 5
Dove, Glenda (flute) 107
Ensemble Ars Nova 152
Esterhazy String Quartet 173
Feinberg, Alan (piano) 177
Field, Richard (viola) 46
Ford, Christine (english horn) 64, 65, 66
Foss, Lukas (conductor) 3
Furness, Albert (chimes) 53, 54, 55, 56
Furness, Albert (percussion) 64, 65, 66
Fussell, Charles (conductor) 173
Gallagher, Maureen (viola) 37